Narrator: Part 5
William: A line of people began trickling through the alleys from the shops and heading in my direction.
They’d seen the tower from the market and were walking towards my house.
I recognized a few of the traders…One asked, ‘What is this thing?...What does it do?’
‘Generates electricity from the wind. I’ll show you.’ ‘That’s impossible,’ he said…
‘Stand back and watch.’…
More and more people arrived…
Looking out, I saw my parents and sisters at the back of the crowd.
‘Let’s see how crazy this boy really is,’ said someone in the crowd.
A steady wind whipped through the rungs of the tower. Here it goes, I thought.
I grabbed the bicycle spoke and jerked it loose. The blades began to turn.
…The tyre spun slowly, creaking at first. Everything was happening in slow motion.
I needed it to go faster.
Come on, I begged. Don’t embarrass me now.
Slowly, the blades picked up speed. Come on, come on.
Just then a gust of wind slammed against my body, and the blades kicked up like mad.
The tower rocked once, knocking me off balance.
I wrapped my elbow around the wooden rung as the blades spun like furious propellers behind my head.
I held the bulb before me, waiting for my miracle. It flickered once.
Just a flash at first, then a surge of bright, magnificent light.
My heart nearly burst. ‘Look,’ someone said. ‘He’s made light!’…
It was glorious light, and it was absolutely mine!
I threw my hands in the air and screamed with joy.
…Dangling now by one arm with the bulb burning bright in my hand,
I looked down at the eyes below, now wide in disbelief.
‘Electric wind!’ I shouted. ‘I told you I wasn’t mad!’
Presenter: William Kamkwamba first used his windmill to provide power for his home,
but it was later used to pump water from the village well and enable the farmers to irrigate their crops.
Since his windmill became a global news story,
William has graduated from college and given acclaimed TED talks.
Now 37, he designs instruction manuals to create low-cost, high-impact,
easy-to-assemble projects in communities around the world.
The film The Boy Who Harnessed the Wind is available to stream on Netflix.